Stephen Shine

81 Timbercroft Lane, Plumstead, London, SE18 2SD 07885 383 727 | stephen.shine88@gmail.com

Profile

I'm a motivated person with an analytical mind. I have very strong communication, problem-solving and people skills. I have experience of working in an agile environment and managing and training people. In my spare time I've studied Java and computer science.

Professional Experience

Financial Ombudsman Service

March 2015 - Present

- OPA Rule Author (two days a week)
 - Maintain and develop software used to help resolve complaints
 - Responsible for improving our most used software which helps to resolve complaints about PPI
 - Analyse processes and existing rules to create user-friendly and efficient solutions
 - Investigate problems with the software and fix them
 - Oversee testing and implementation of software, making sure it integrates with our case handling software

Financial Ombudsman Service

October 2012 - Present

Adjudicator (three days a week since March 2015)

- Investigate complaints about the sale and administration of PPI policies
- Analyse information given by consumers and businesses, and take into account the law and regulations to decide what's fair
- Communicate the outcome of my investigation using easy to understand language
- Give support and advice to colleagues about complaints they're dealing with

Royal Bank of Scotland (NatWest)

April 2012 - October 2012

Team Leader

- Managed a team of up to 15 complaint handlers, setting targets, providing motivation and conducting quality checks
- Delivered training on technical subjects and presented operational information to senior management
- Developed and introduced Lean change to the department and assisted in designing and implementing more efficient complaint handling process

Royal Bank of Scotland (NatWest)

June 2011 - April 2012

Case Handler

- Investigated complaints for business customers about products and services
- Managed my own caseload and assisted in the management of the workload for the department
- Supported new staff by taking technical queries and checking the quality of their work

Royal Bank of Scotland (NatWest)

November 2010 - June 2011

Customer Service Advisor

- Answered inbound customer queries about their business account, such as wage payments
- Handled technical queries for new and existing members of staff

Professional qualifications

- PRINCE2 Foundation Certificate result 86% (October 2015)
- OPA Rule Specialist Foundation Program result 94% (March 2015)
- Level 3 Certificate in Insurance (January 2015)

Education

York University MA Music Technology

2009 - 2010

- The course focused on the physical aspects of sound and the theory of digital sound processing, and how this can be practically applied to software
- Created a software instrument using the visual based program Max MSP that was used by the entire course to create a piece of coursework
- Designed a piece of software for my dissertation using C++ programming language that allowed the user to interact with sound through visual feedback

University of Hull

2006 - 2009

BA (Hons) Creative Music Technology (2:1)

- The course focused on the use of technology within music and the social and cultural context of music
- Created interactive software using Max MSP to track the movements of a dancer and interpret the data to manipulate live audio and video
- Established and ran a record label, including the creation and distribution of CDs and records, and organised local music events
- Earned the prize for outstanding contribution to the university upon graduation

Bishop Vesey's Grammar School

1999 - 2006

A-level qualifications: Economics, English Literature & Language, Music